<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Jenner Hanni</title>
		<description>Adventures of an aerospace geek in Portland, Oregon.</description>
		<link></link>
		<atom:link href="feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>L1 at NXRS 2014</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I went out to Brothers, Oregon, to Oregon Rocketry&amp;#8217;s annual Northwest Xtreme Rocket Show in hopes of getting my Level 1 and Level 2 certs with my black and yellow 4&amp;quot; Sentinel on a 38mm motor I intended to buy out there. It turns out I forget to take pictures when I&amp;#8217;m busy chasing rockets, but these are a few right before the first flight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-fZB1zFGWsmw/U7NhnJTOUFI/AAAAAAAAGlw/Bfmzf32N7s8/w484-h645-no/sentinel-nxrs2014.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-hF7FB7399kY/U7Nhc80VVPI/AAAAAAAAGlU/zEeG5qpA2dI/w484-h645-no/photo5.png&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for my L1 on a Cesaroni H225 motor and it lifted off the pad all right but toward the end of the burn, the motor&amp;#8217;s o-ring failed and it CATOed. Luckily it was high enough that the force separated the rocket and ejected the parachute. Unfortunately, the retaining ring retained the nozzle of the motor while the motor casing shot out the front of the rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rocket floated down to a fairly soft landing in a sage bush behind the flightline and I had two good bearings from people who&amp;#8217;d seen the motor casing come down, so I recovered all the pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob from Sunriver Observatory cheerfully replaced the motor casing and motor, which was fantastic, but he didn&amp;#8217;t have any more H225s so I accepted an H125 instead. The models predicted a very low and slow flight but I collected second opinions and decided to go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cleaned up the rocket and discovered the end of the tube against which the motor retaining ring fits was eaten through on one side so I cut a two-inch piece of cardboard motor package and glued it around for stability. I built the new motor, waited over night to Sunday morning with calm wind, and lit it off at 8am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It lifted really, really, realllllllly slow and then I didn&amp;#8217;t have the ejection timing quite right so it waited a lonnnnnnnnnnng time after apogee to finally blow and separate. My (acting?) prefect walked out with me to recover it and discovered another rocket had landed on it, shock cords crossing. We untangled them and found a pristine rocket, no zippering, no shredding, nothing. It&amp;#8217;s basically built like a tank so it looks great and it&amp;#8217;s ready to fly again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-f7pmKNivktI/U7NhdXdzTkI/AAAAAAAAGlc/GwQwJ9E_SfY/w484-h645-no/photo6.png&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-jg-H2vaUX6k/U7NhbqEbLaI/AAAAAAAAGk8/k7cCm2cdYHU/w484-h645-no/photo2.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-fc0_YnquP6k/U7NheCIoWMI/AAAAAAAAGlo/vQgNolL3OZE/w860-h645-no/photo8.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-_j1sJ_OSdmk/U7NhbjxLMMI/AAAAAAAAGlE/AN7TYVw692I/w860-h645-no/photo1.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-btMlKw9jgFY/U7NhbmhbGMI/AAAAAAAAGk0/EYrm0e6r2jI/w860-h645-no/photo3.png&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/nxrs-2014</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/nxrs-2014</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Breadboard to PCB</title>
				<description>&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 20px; padding: 20px; float: left; background-color: #f5b400; color: #fff;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;COOKING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;float:left; padding: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Open Hardware from Breadboard to &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensourcebridge.org/sessions/1314&quot;&gt;conference talk I gave at Open Source Bridge 2014&lt;/a&gt; on June 26, 2014, at the Eliot Center in Portland, Oregon. I brought a handful of random printed circuit boards I&amp;#8217;ve built in the last year and used a lot of photos to walk through the process of drawing the circuit, routing the board, and assembling the finished product. It was meant to be for people who&amp;#8217;ve built breadboard circuits but would like to do their own printed circuit boards; the idea was to at least walk through the process once to introduce some Googleable vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to Georgia Reh and Bart Massey for advising, helping, morally supporting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the 15Mb Beamer presentation &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wicker/open-hardware-talk/raw/master/from-breadboard-to-pcb.pdf&quot;&gt;directly&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wicker/open-hardware-talk&quot;&gt;Github repo has all the source files, including images.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excerpt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;#8217;ve built a breadboard circuit with wires everywhere. What&amp;#8217;s next? A printed circuit board! I&amp;#8217;ll talk about your open hardware development options through the lens of my recent project turning a breadboard prototype into a finished Arduino shield for a curing oven at Portland State.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rocket manufacturing capstone team recently built a curing oven at Portland State. They wrote a first version of Arduino code and wired up a simple breadboard circuit so the oven worked but the department wanted them to make the oven as appliance-like as possible. The team continued on with its capstone project while I cleaned up the electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll walk you through the hardware development process. I made two revisions of through-hole printed circuit boards using the router at the Electronics Prototyping Lab at Portland State. Then I modified the design to interface between an Arduino and an Adafruit display shield. The final surface mount version went off to OSHPark, a locally-run &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll bring all three versions of the boards and we’ll talk through what, how, and why they turned out the way they did — particularly why I used Eagle instead of the open source KiCad, when to use surface mount vs through-hole parts, the trade-offs in quality of circuit boards and when to make the jump to OSHPark, cost of components, how to navigate Mouser or Digikey as opposed to Adafruit or Sparkfun, what open source license to use, and further resources for open hardware in the Portland area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not evangelizing the Arduino, only using it as an example, so I’ll bring and briefly introduce it but you don’t have to be familiar. The talk will be friendly to complete beginners but it’s intended to be very useful to anyone with some experience building breadboard circuits who wants to take the next step.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/osbridge-open-hardware</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/osbridge-open-hardware</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>GPS RF Front-end Board</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Portland State University&amp;#8217;s Maseeh College of Engineering and Computer Science runs an innovation program that awards small thousand-dollar grants to students working on interesting projects. In 2011 there were a handful of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;-related projects that needed a way to work directly with the raw I/Q data coming from the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; satellites before any processing or correlating had been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercial off-the-shelf &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; receivers are cheap and ubiquitous but they don&amp;#8217;t expose that data. One of my mentors, Andrew Greenberg, developed an open source &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; receiver for his Masters thesis in 2005 and suggested I take a look at doing the same thing with current hardware. I said I would if he would help, so together we built a board, built a revision, and are in the process of figuring out what modifications will be needed for a third.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board isn&amp;#8217;t a full &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; receiver. Instead, it&amp;#8217;s an &amp;#8220;RF front end&amp;#8221; board that has a MAX2769 Universal &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; Receiver chip to read the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; signals and pass them out over something that looks a lot like &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SPI&lt;/span&gt; but isn&amp;#8217;t. We chose to place an STM32F407 microcontroller running the ChibiOS embedded operating system on the board to support streaming the data out over Ethernet and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;. We exposed the raw pins over a header between the MAX2769 and STM32F407 to allow a user to skip the microcontroller entirely. We also included an SD card to log the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board does not currently support a battery so it must be powered over &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; or Ethernet at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is open hardware and software licensed under the 3-clause &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;BSD&lt;/span&gt; license and maintained on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://psas.pdx.edu/&quot;&gt;Portland State Aerospace Society&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/psas/&quot;&gt;Github account&lt;/a&gt;. You can find the bill of materials and Eagle schematics at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/psas/gps-rf-board/&quot;&gt;psas/gps-rf-board&lt;/a&gt; and the software as part of &lt;a href=&quot;http://githbu.com/psas/stm32/&quot;&gt;psas/stm32&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Board Layout Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/gpsboard/functional-block.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board has four layers and was ordered from &lt;a href=&quot;http://oshpark.com&quot;&gt;OSHPark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Power&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can power the board from Rocketnet Ethernet (up to 20V) or over &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; (about 5V) so we used an LMZ12001 switching regulator with an input voltage range from 4.5V to 20V to output 3.3V for the digital side of the board. We then used two ultra-low noise MAX8510 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LDO&lt;/span&gt; linear regulators to provide 2.85V on separate digital and analog supply lines for the RF side of the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://datasheets.maximintegrated.com/en/ds/MAX2769.pdf&quot;&gt;MAX2769&lt;/a&gt; is a tiny 28-pin universal &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; Receiver with a 1.4dB noise figure. The datasheet says we don&amp;#8217;t need external &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SAW&lt;/span&gt; filters but we used them anyway. The chip has two &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LNA&lt;/span&gt; inputs and the eval kit is set up for to support both passive and active antennas. We used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://datasheets.maximintegrated.com/en/ds/MAX2769EVKIT.pdf&quot;&gt;MAX2769 Eval Kit&lt;/a&gt; as a reference but it was a particularly difficult schematic to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our board has a single antenna attachment point with a couple of optional circuits that the user chooses by where you populate capacitors and resistors. Option #1 is whether or not to have an LNA1 and its &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ANTBIAS&lt;/span&gt;-pin power circuit. Option #2 is whether to put into LNA1 or LNA2 on the chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/gpsboard/v2-rf-section.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use a 100-pin &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; Cortex-M3 STM32F407 running the Portland State Aerospace Society&amp;#8217;s version of ChibiOS to program the MAX2769 and to support &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;, Ethernet, and an SD card. We also break out raw data signals at pin test points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethernet requires the Portland State Aerospace Society&amp;#8217;s Rocketnet connector for programming, data streaming, and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A micro-&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; connector is available for programming, data streaming, and power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The micro-SD card is available for data logging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The serial breakout is two 1&amp;#215;11 0.1&amp;quot; headers which we also used for debug. We ran traces between the two breakouts because we were unsure about some of the pinouts from the MAX2769 and wanted to be sure we could cut traces and easily run modwire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Build&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/gpsboard/gpsboard-v2-build.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the board installed on the avionics module that carries the flight computer, sensor packages, and battery packs. The green board on top is the commercial Crescent &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; unit. The purple board down below is the JennerGPS. They&amp;#8217;re both connected to the splitter in the middle, which runs off to the cylindrical patch antenna on the skin of the rocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;/images/project/gpsboard/gpssystem.png&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current Status&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board was flown on the Portland State Aerospace Society&amp;#8217;s LV2.3 airframe for Launch 11 on July 20th, 2014, in Brothers, Oregon, to an altitude of 15,000 feet. The hardware was complete but the software on the board was not entirely ready for launch and, anyway, the entire &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; system failed so no data was retrieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the launch is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://psas.pdx.edu/launch11/&quot;&gt;the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PSAS&lt;/span&gt; Launch 11 page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Links and References&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/psas/gps-rf-board/&quot;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt; has all the schematics. The current version is v2. We welcome collaboration but do please contact us before using the schematics because the repo may not have all current modifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was super helpful to reference &lt;a href=&quot;http://swift-nav.com/piksi.html&quot;&gt;Swift Navigation&amp;#8217;s Piksi &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/span&gt; Receiver&lt;/a&gt; which uses the MAX2769 chip with an STM32F407 and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FPGA&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first version of this board was funded by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pdx.edu/cecs/innovation-program&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MCECS&lt;/span&gt; Innovation Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/gps-board-v2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/gps-board-v2</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rocket Manufacturing Capstone</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The Portland State Aerospace Society is a fifteen-year old rocket club that puts really interesting, sophisticated electronics to stream back live rocket flight data and video in a thick, heavy, over-engineered metal airframe. It&amp;#8217;s occasionally been nice to have an overly durable airframe but most of the time it&amp;#8217;s just a pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got lucky enough this year to convince veterans of Portland State&amp;#8217;s Formula &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SAE&lt;/span&gt; team to not only design a carbon fiber rocket for their senior year mechanical engineering capstone, but to develop a manufacturing process for us electrical engineers and document the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as we&amp;#8217;re concerned, it turned into basically the best capstone ever. Their deliverables included a layup table, a 4&amp;#8242;&amp;#215;4&amp;#8242;&amp;#215;8&amp;#8242; curing oven, smaller mandrels for testing, lots of crushed and nearly-crushed modules from their strength tests, full-sized final mandrels for the final six-inch rocket, several regular rocket sections, one motor section, the retaining rings, an electronics carrier insert, prototype fins, a block of super-dense foam for the nose cone, and thousands of dollars in layup materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked with the team to develop the oven control box and I&amp;#8217;m working with them into the summer to develop the &lt;a href=&quot;http://psas.github.io/mme-capstone/&quot;&gt;rocket manufacturing page&lt;/a&gt; to store all the documentation. We&amp;#8217;re releasing everything as open source hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They brought all their deliverables out to the Engineering Building plaza for the final capstone shindig right before graduation so I went down to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/rocket-manufacturing-capstone</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/06/rocket-manufacturing-capstone</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rocket Avionics Drop Test</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a drop tower at Portland State which runs the height of the six stories of the Engineering Building&amp;#8217;s atrium. Dr. Weislogel at Portland State uses it to do &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;-funded capillary action research. There&amp;#8217;s a container that you bring up to the top and you place your items to be tested in the container, hanging by a cord, and the container takes care of the air resistance for you while your item essentially experiences microgravity or free-fall until it hits the high Gs when it comes to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got permission to take our rocket avionics module and do a drop test in the tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nathan put up an iPython notebook that&amp;#8217;s web-browsable with the full data write-up. &lt;a href=&quot;http://nbviewer.ipython.org/url/psas.github.io/Launch-11/droptest/2014-05-16-drop-1/results.ipynb?create=1&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of these are my photos. It&amp;#8217;s a pretty sweet setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-3paYwKYGQwc/U9IDYDg6cJI/AAAAAAAAGo8/_ofUWWk6ujE/w489-h652-no/IMG_1629.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-XYu3z37aQWI/U9IDYlaJEYI/AAAAAAAAGpA/G4cs9JkgSCA/w489-h652-no/IMG_1631.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-Kkh49Og5lrs/U9IDYNteszI/AAAAAAAAGo4/zbSKtkf9Eo0/w488-h651-no/IMG_1632.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-jfl0RrHBVuk/U9IDal-1GZI/AAAAAAAAGpU/DOf2V6prLAU/w488-h651-no/IMG_1654.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-zvL_cEqgjmM/U9IFjDWJfkI/AAAAAAAAGpo/0y2mu6O4El0/w800-h600-no/IMG_1646.JPG&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/drop-test</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/drop-test</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Opal Creek</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I went down to Salem for breakfast and then headed up through Elkhorn Valley to the Opal Creek Trailhead. Way too many people around and the bridge was out in Jawbone Flats so I hiked just about to the loop trail fork and then went back. I took more time to check out the mine entrances and to explore down by the river. Found a millipede and had some fun thinking of millipede robots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this hike is definitely past Jawbone Flats at the Opal pools but the whole area is beautiful so it was a nice day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/7QkvHKyEzLC_TIuRWkoEapAu1578x0GLKp5M7n5tFw=w900-h242-no&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/opalcreek/1.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/opalcreek/2.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/opalcreek/3.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-jc73ihRtR_M/U4oT3mDddZI/AAAAAAAAGiQ/0hAENfU5eEQ/w900-h288-no/IMG_1786.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-LM8Gj6qXppw/U4oTaKZQB_I/AAAAAAAAGg0/YMbSuUSeGRU/w869-h652-no/IMG_1789.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-bgpJt-uVtuk/U4oTa9rGnsI/AAAAAAAAGh4/vQKGWsVrfJM/w869-h652-no/IMG_1792.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-QwdT59CWGUw/U4oTbDeYYvI/AAAAAAAAGhw/1jYyXSjRJM4/w869-h652-no/IMG_1797.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-cB_IHyScM58/U4oTbQ8m0rI/AAAAAAAAGhM/ysW_77xWZLQ/w869-h652-no/IMG_1801.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-HNeba0H35FU/U4oTb1hvwFI/AAAAAAAAGhY/brOFi5YVy4U/w869-h652-no/IMG_1807.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ZXi8cFiltzY/U4oTcL3vwPI/AAAAAAAAGhc/PG6d9qLLj84/w869-h652-no/IMG_1809.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-1KVHcrx-ioA/U4oTcnXKpjI/AAAAAAAAGho/nB7GCx80WVQ/w869-h652-no/IMG_1810.JPG&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/opal-creek</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/opal-creek</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>STM32F4-Discovery Breakout Board</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The STM32F4-Discovery board is a really great dev board that breaks out all the pins to, unfortunately, male headers. All of my sensors have male pins so I finally gave up daisy-chaining female-to-male jumpers and decided to make a breakout board on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LPKF&lt;/span&gt; router in the Electronics Prototyping Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to find Jason Lopez&amp;#8217;s Eagle schematic and footprint but I had trouble with the drills so I changed the drill size. Otherwise it saved me a ton of time and effort. Thanks, Jason!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the schematic and board layout for the two-layer board. It&amp;#8217;s really a one-layer board, as the vias aren&amp;#8217;t plated. I ran all the traces on the bottom side of the board so I could place the female headers through from the top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/stm32f4discovery/discovery-breakout-sch.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/stm32f4discovery/discovery-breakout-brd.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four female headers so the dev board doesn&amp;#8217;t have to be soldered in and four more for the jumpers to attach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/stm32f4discovery/IMG_1838.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/stm32f4discovery/IMG_1839.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/stm32f4discovery/IMG_1840.JPG&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/stm32f4-discovery-breakout</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/stm32f4-discovery-breakout</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Garden Update</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re having our usual scattered, unpredictable mix of thunderstorms, warm rain, hail, brilliant sunshine, and blue skies, so the garden has exploded in size over the last couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The irrigation stuff arrived. My cat approves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/garden2/IMG_1663_crop.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/garden2/IMG_1669.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/garden2/IMG_1670.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/garden2/IMG_1673.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My boss started tomatoes from seed and ended up with too many so I now have way more tomatoes than I know what to do with. I&amp;#8217;m going to move over some of the broccoli and cabbage from the right-hand box to the tomato box to make some room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/garden2/IMG_1674.JPG&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/garden-update</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/garden-update</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>McCall Point</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I went with some friends up to McCall Point on the plateau east of Mosier, Oregon, for a Mother&amp;#8217;s Day hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we stopped briefly in Mosier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-H_UvL1FRdNs/U3PC2K_G4eI/AAAAAAAAGck/FFVHPUI-h78/w489-h652-no/095.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we headed up to the plateau and started off towards McCall Point. It&amp;#8217;s a little less than 1100&amp;#8217; elevation gain over two miles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-bw4YYg-c3-g/U3PC3ffKuvI/AAAAAAAAGdA/x1I9dhGV08w/w800-h600-no/113.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the Washington State town of Lyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-JDlC8gnmnAo/U3PC3YJQoBI/AAAAAAAAGc0/i7Jh3ZLCLD0/w800-h600-no/120.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-TteVE4zTmsc/U3PC34ktqKI/AAAAAAAAGc4/k3nYr6KLS68/w800-h600-no/130.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-6oDnMIwBvJQ/U3PC5rkpcoI/AAAAAAAAGdg/TPSz1uBi0jg/w800-h600-no/134.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-j-fCJoHO3e8/U3PC6NAXWsI/AAAAAAAAGdc/FZcglWMF9-Q/w800-h600-no/150.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-xL7BFwxpQwg/U3PC7MBwPqI/AAAAAAAAGdw/5TALuso2sQk/w800-h600-no/151.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/project/misc/mccall-blended.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ED8ngLYasLU/U3PC8tzai_I/AAAAAAAAGeM/7KhnsUncAZs/w800-h600-no/156.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-u1Ofr4DYDcI/U3PC8i27lyI/AAAAAAAAGeE/CmKm3Gi8srw/w800-h600-no/157.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trail loops around the meadow at the top, perfect for a picnic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-2zWNs0tTXsI/U3PC9PuxTWI/AAAAAAAAGeU/ECckBPTZR5c/w800-h600-no/178.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-oVFJnsVkiPo/U3PC9vuc20I/AAAAAAAAGeg/MTvZQFSPc94/w800-h600-no/183.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-C-dwR9EvHTQ/U3PC-fGlT_I/AAAAAAAAGec/5D8WwKxgGfw/w800-h600-no/184.JPG&quot;&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/mccall-point</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/mccall-point</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Marlboro College</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine went off to a tiny liberal arts college on a hilltop in Vermont to get a philosophy and literature degree, which might be the exact opposite of what I&amp;#8217;ve done in every way, so I went out to visit him shortly before graduation. I arrived in Boston just after midnight, rented a car, and drove through New Hampshire to Vermont.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just some photos for my own memories. The woods in particular were beautiful. Marlboro, like the rest of the East Coast, experienced a super cold winter that lingered into May, though I guess the snow had melted right before I got there. Walking and talking on the trails was satisfying, and everywhere there were glimpses of other people having been there: sculptures, little shrines, art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/007.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/012.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dalrymple and the back of the library. I didn&amp;#8217;t take many photos since I was too busy hanging out, but I wanted to have something visual to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/022.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/023.JPG&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googly eyes stuck on National Geographic cut-outs around the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/024.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;img class=&quot;vertimg&quot; src=&quot;/images/travels/marlboro/032.JPG&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/marlboro-college-vermont</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.wickerbox.net//2014/05/marlboro-college-vermont</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
